

# **Axel Alavedra**

Programmer

# About

#### Phone:

+34 667 75 75 18

### Email:

axel.alavedra@gmail.com

### Portfolio:

axelalavedra.com

### Linkedin:

Axel Alavedra Cabello

### Address:

Terrassa, Barcelona, Spain

### Languages

English: High
Spanish: Native
Catalan: Native

### **Profile**

Programmer with over four years of experience in the video game industry and shipped PC/Console titles.

My areas of expertise are Gameplay and AI, with excellent software design and debugging skills.

Great passion for making games and working together with design teams.

### **Career Summary**

## Sep 2023 - Present

### Al Programmer at Melbot

- Unreal Engine, GAS
- Al Behaviors
- Al Combat Systems
- Al Decision Making & Tools
- Gameplay mechanics

### Sep 2021 - Sep 2023

# Gameplay Programmer at

### <u>Melbot</u>

- Unity
- Development Tools
- Gameplay mechanics
- Al Behaviors
- Al Systems & Tools:
  - Behavior Tree Tool
  - Position Query System Tool
  - Combat Circle System
  - Perception System

# July 2021 - Sep 2021

# Intern Programmer at Melbot

- Unity
- Gameplay mechanics
- Al Behaviors
- Sole developer for PS4 port

# October 2016 - May 2017 Intern Programmer at ViOD

### Games Studio

- Player actions
- Al Behaviors
- Gameplay mechanics
- Scoring system

### **Professional Skills**

### **Programming:**

C++, C#

#### AI:

State Machine, Behavior Tree, Utility Al, Decision Making, Pathfinding

### **Game Engines:**

Unity, Unreal Engine

### **Development:**

Debugging, Profiling, Architecture Design

### **Shipped Titles**

- My Little Pony: A Maretime Bay Adventure
- <u>Projects: Nick Jr. Party</u>
   <u>Adventure</u>

### **Educational Training**

## CITM (UPC)

# Bachelor's degree in Design and Development of Videogames

• Attended from Sept. 2017 to June 2021

### **Escola PIA Balmes**

Certificate of Higher Education, Computer Games and Programming Skills

- Attended from Sept. 2015 to June 2017
- Unity Certified Programmer